navisite.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy | Spectrum Enterprise | Navisite

## Contents

## Introduction

This Privacy Policy applies to Navisite.com, Navisite.co.uk, and navicloud.navisite.com (the "Websites") owned and operated by Navisite, LLC ("Navisite", "We", "Us"). This Privacy Policy describes how Navisite collects, uses, and discloses your personal information. It also describes the choices available to you and the rights you may have in relation to your personal information.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information we collect through our services. Please see our separate notice at Annex A regarding the way in which we handle this information.

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or Navisite’s practices, please [contact us](mailto:webinfo@navisite.com) using the contact details set out below under [Contact Us](mailto:webinfo@navisite.com).

## Data collection

When using the Websites and registering for a newsletter or requesting more information, you often must first complete the registration form. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as first and last name, email address and company name, etc.). We use this information to contact you about the services offered by Navisite in which you have expressed interest and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy. We obtain all necessary permissions before doing this where required by local applicable law.

You have the option to provide demographic information (such as number of employees, industry, geographic region, etc.) to us; we encourage you to submit this information so we can provide you a more personalized experience on our Websites and in any responsive materials. We may also use this information as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

Navisite is the sole owner of the information collected on the Websites. Navisite collects personal information from our users at several different points on our Websites.

Personal information in this context is identifying information about an individual (such as a name, title, company name, address, email address and phone number), as well as any other information which relates to an identified or identifiable individual. Additional or missing public information – such as your company location and industry, etc. – may be appended with the aid of third-party sources (for example third party event and tradeshow organizers) for sales and marketing purposes and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

Navisite may also collect IP addresses and/or domain names (where applicable) of visitors to the Websites, the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email and information volunteered by the user, such as survey information and/or Website registrations. Navisite may use this information to help diagnose problems and to administer the Websites and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

Access to certain of Navisite's web pages are accessible only by email invitation containing a link to a private site created specifically for the intended user (the **"Microsite"** ). Information that a user provides to us within the Microsite may be used for permission purposes, tracking information on how often users access their Microsite and which documents they view to give Navisite feedback on the effectiveness of its content. We may also use this information as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

## Links to third-party websites

Navisite Websites contains links to other sites owned and maintained by companies other than Navisite. Those companies’ privacy practices may differ from Navisite’s. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. Navisite is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. Users should check the applicable privacy policy of such linked websites.

Our Websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## How we use your personal information

The information Navisite collects may be used to: 

  * provide, maintain, protect and personalize our services;
  * improve the content of the Websites;
  * customize the content and/or layout of the Websites’ pages for each individual user;
  * notify users about updates to the Website(s);
  * respond to requests for information;
  * send newsletters;
  * assess applications such as partner and job applications;
  * contact you with marketing and offers relating to products and services offered by us (unless you have opted out of marketing, or we are otherwise prevented by law from doing so);
  * personalize the marketing messages we send you;
  * Shared with trusted vendors that partner with Navisite to deliver technology and support services in which you express interest. Where required by local law, we will obtain your consent before doing this;
  * deal with your enquiries and requests;
  * cooperate with regulators and law enforcement bodies;
  * communicate with you regarding your account or changes to our policies, terms and conditions;
  * resolve complaints, as well as handle requests for data access or correction;
  * protect your, our or others' rights and interests; or
  * as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy. 

## Legal grounds for using your personal information

Some jurisdictions require a legal basis to use or process your personal information. In most cases the legal basis will be one of the following: 

  * to fulfill any contractual obligations we may have to you. Failure to provide this information may prevent or delay the fulfillment of these contractual obligations;
  * in order to comply with our legal obligations, for example to keep records of any services we provide you with as required by applicable law or regulation, or to comply with any governmental, quasi-governmental or court orders or subpoenas;
  * where there is a public interest in the processing, for example where it is necessary in order to prevent and detect fraud; and
  * to meet our or a third party's legitimate interests, for example to understand how you use our services and to enable us to derive knowledge from that to develop new services, to protect our rights or the rights of third parties, or to resolve any disputes. When we process personal information to meet our legitimate interests, we put in place robust safeguards to help ensure that your privacy is protected and that our legitimate interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.

We may also obtain your consent to collect and use certain types of personal information, including when we are required to do so by law (for example, in certain jurisdictions where consent is always required to collect personal information, or in relation to our direct marketing activities or use of tracking technologies, or if we process certain types of particularly sensitive personal information about you). If we ask for your consent to process your personal information, you may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us using the details at the end of this Privacy Policy.

## Data sharing

The information Navisite collects may be shared with third–party service providers for commercial purposes for services in which you express interest. Where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent before doing this. Navisite provides your information to trusted vendors who work on behalf of or with Navisite and under confidentiality agreements to provide services such as help desk management and archiving services. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information.

Our Websites offer publicly accessible blogs and testimonials. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, [contact us](http://go.navisite.com/Preference_Center.html) at our preference center.

We work closely with other businesses and companies that are affiliated to us including Charter Communications, Inc. and its affiliates and subsidiaries. We may share your personal information with other companies within our corporate group for marketing purposes (subject to applicable laws or regulations), internal reporting and other purposes as described in this Privacy Policy.

Navisite shares your personal information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to Navisite's property or the physical safety of any person, violations of Navisite’s terms of use, respond to law enforcement requests, subpoenas, legal process or inquiries, or as otherwise required by law.

Navisite also shares your personal information in the event that Navisite, or any affiliated entity, or substantially all of its assets related to a particular geographical region, are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, reorganization, consolidation or liquidation, user information may be one of the transferred assets.

In addition, we may share your personal information with your consent or as otherwise disclosed at the time of collection.

Aggregate data and information that otherwise is not personally identifiable to you may be disclosed to others.

## International data transfer

We may transfer certain personal information across geographical borders to our subsidiaries or service providers (working in conjunction with us or on our behalf) worldwide. Such transfers are made in accordance with applicable law.

Where you are based in the European Union you should be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country that is not regarded as ensuring an adequate level of protection for personal information under European Union law.

We have put in place appropriate safeguards (such as contractual commitments) in accordance with applicable legal requirements to ensure that your personal information is adequately protected. For more information on the appropriate safeguards in place, please contact us at the details below.

## Automated decisions about you

We do not automatically process your personal information to make decisions or conduct 'profiling' about you.

## Security and data retention

Navisite uses reasonable efforts to treat all consumer information, not just the sensitive and private information mentioned above, in a confidential manner. For example, the Websites, where technically feasible, enforce the encryption of sensitive data in transit using technologies such as secure socket layer (SSL). For managed messaging services, object layer encryption and transport layer encryption (TLS) are used to secure messages. Although Navisite has a base layer of security for all clients, each environment has additional controls that are sized and positioned based on individual client requirements. Navisite observes the core security concept, CIA Triad, of protecting the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of data. The policies, procedures, guidelines, baselines, and standards employed by Navisite in conjunction with the client’s team follow industry standard practices, where feasible. If you have any questions about security on our Websites, you can [contact us](mailto::webinfo@navisite.com) using the details provided below.

We will only retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide the services, maintain business records for analysis and/or audit purposes, comply with record retention requirements under the law, defend or bring any existing or potential legal claims, deal with disputes, and deal with any complaints regarding our services.

## Use of cookies and other tracking technologies

We, and our partners, affiliates, or analytics and online service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Websites, tracking users’ movements around the Websites and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of the information on our Websites to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We and our third party partners use Local Storage (HTML5) to provide certain features on our Website, to display advertising based on your web browsing activity, and/or to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

Navisite does not correlate this information with directly identifying information about individual users, with the exception of users of our Microsite. Navisite may provide aggregated cookie data to third parties for analysis purposes. Navisite is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

If you prefer not to receive cookies on Navisite’s Websites, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use any area of Navisite’s Websites.

Some of our websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies or other tracking technologies to help us analyze how users interact with and use Navisite’s Websites, compile reports on the websites’ activity, and provide other services related to website activity and usage. The technologies used by Google may collect information such as your IP address, time of visit, whether you are a return visitor, and any referring website. Navisite’s Websites do not use Google Analytics to gather information that personally identifies you and Google has committed not to re-identify the information it collects without your affirmative consent. The information generated by Google Analytics will be transmitted to and stored by Google and will be subject to Google’s [privacy policies](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). To learn more about Google’s partner services and to learn how to opt out of tracking of analytics by Google click [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our Websites to gather information about your activities on the Websites over time and on other sites to provide you advertising based on your browsing activities and interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt out by clicking here <http://go.navisite.com/Preference_Center.html> If you are located in the European Union, [click here](http://go.navisite.com/Preference_Center.html). Please note that this does not opt you out of being served ads; you will continue to receive generic ads.

We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

## Your rights over your personal information

Subject to local laws, you may have certain rights regarding your personal information. These include rights to: 

  * access your personal information
  * rectify the information we hold about you
  * erase your personal information
  * restrict our use of your personal information
  * object to our use of your personal information
  * receive your personal information in a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (right to data portability)
  * lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority.

We encourage you to contact us to update or correct your information using the contact details below if it changes or if the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate.

We will contact you if we need additional information from you in order to honor your requests.

If you would like to discuss or exercise such rights, please contact us using the details below.

We will respond to your requests within a reasonable timeframe and any deadlines specified by local applicable law.

## Your communication preferences

Through the Websites, Navisite provides users with the opportunity to subscribe to various sales and marketing communications. These communications include updates about Navisite, promotions, press releases, events, in the news information, and career opportunities. Users can update email preferences, or unsubscribe from Navisite sales and marketing communications, by updating their email preferences within the [Navisite Email Preference Center](http://go.navisite.com/Preference_Center.html), or by sending an email to Navisite at [webinfo@navisite.com](mailto:webinfo@navisite.com)

## Contact us

If you have any questions about the security on our Websites, you can contact us using the details below. 

  * You can send an email to webinfo@navisite.com.
  * You can phone us at +1 978-682-8300 ATTN: Marketing Department
  * You can send mail using following postal address:
  * Navisite, LLC ATTN: Marketing Department 400 Minuteman Road Andover, MA 01810

## Notification of changes

Please check our Privacy Policy periodically as Navisite reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Changes to Navisite's Privacy Policy will be posted to the Websites. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.

If, however, we are going to use users' personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by email or by posting a prominent notice on our Websites prior to implementing the change.

## Annex A

## Notice regarding information collected through the Navisite services.

The use of information collected through our services shall be limited to the purpose of providing the services for which the Client has engaged Navisite.

Navisite may, in certain circumstances, have personal information of its clients’ clients transmitted into its data centers and has no direct relationship with the personal data of individuals of its clients. If you are a client of one of our clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our clients.

Any personal information that is transmitted in the provision of services will be processed or retained only as long as needed to provide services to our clients. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to Navisite’s client (the data controller).
